And what is the typical administration
route for progesterone for women? I
predominantly uh choose progesterone
capsules, oral capsules. I think they
work fantastically well. Um I know
there's a some people would argue that a
sublingual route is better. And I like
sublingual too, but in particular, a lot
of my female patients are coming to me
because they are anxious. Uh because
they're not getting a good night's
sleep. And these are all things that
oral progesterone happen to have a
tremendous benefit because oral
progesterone is going to go through your
liver. It's going to go through
something called the first pass effect
and it's going to be heavily metabolized
into something called alopregnanolone
which is a a metabolite of progesterone
and is that kind of nervous system. Uh
it's the brakes to the brain. It helps
you feel calm and relaxed. It helps you
feel sleepy. Uh so my women love it.
They get a great night's sleep and they
wake up not feeling anxious. Um women
some women just do not tolerate that. Uh
they they feel way too groggy when they
wake up. And again I'll use a sublingual
um you know a troy like a lozenge.
Right. Yeah. And those work fantastic.